Behind every great love is a great story.
The Notebook is a romance, drama film directed by Nick Cassavetes.
An epic love story centered around an older man who
reads aloud to a woman with Alzheimer's.
From a faded notebook, the old man's words bring to life the story about a couple who is separated by World War
II, and is then passionately reunited, seven years later, after they have taken different paths.
Noah Calhoun, played by Ryan Gosling.
Allie Hamilton, played by Rachel McAdams.
Older Allie, played by Gena Rowlands.
Duke, played by James Garner.
Anne Hamilton, played by Joan Allen.
John Hamilton, played by David Thornton.
The Notebook is a 2004 American romantic drama film directed by Nick Cassavetes, from a
screenplay by Jeremy Leven and Jan Sardi, and based on the 1996 novel by Nicholas Sparks.
The film stars Ryan Gosling and Rachel McAdams as a
young couple who fall in love in the 1940s.
Their story is read from a notebook in the modern day by an elderly
man telling the tale to a fellow nursing home resident.
The Notebook had its world premiere at the Seattle International Film Festival on May 20, 2004, and
was theatrically released in the United States on June 25, 2004 by New Line Cinema.
Despite generally mixed reviews from critics, Gosling and McAdams
were singled out for praise for their performances.
The film was a sleeper hit at the box office, grossing $118.3 million against its $29
million budget, and has become a cult classic in the years since its release.
On November 11, 2012, an extended version premiered on ABC Family with
deleted scenes added back into the original storyline.
The film earned several accolades, including the MTV Movie Award for Best
Kiss for Gosling and McAdams at the 2005 MTV Movie Awards.
At the 11th Screen Actors Guild Awards, James Garner was nominated for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Supporting Role
and the director's mother, Gena Rowlands, won Best Supporting Actress – Drama at the 9th Golden Satellite Awards.
The film explores themes of secret love, soulmates, based on
novel or book, love of one's life, fight.
The tone is emotional.